Svante Pahlman

Storgårdsgatan 2, Pargas 21600, Finland +358 44 2910135 svante.pahlman@live.com

SUMMARY

25 years of executive B2B and B2C experience including project management in challenging environments, development of new products and services, development and implementation of business strategies, HR responsibilities.

I want to work in an environment where it is possible to apply my "helicopter view", strategic thinking, analytical and communication skills with the obvious goal of making things better.



EDUCATION

2020	Columbia Business School / Emeritus Executive Education –
	Digital Strategies for Business
2014	Energiatodistuksen laatijan koulutus
2013	Suomen Suunnistusliitto – Suunnistusvalmentajan tutkinto
1992	Åbo Akademi University, DI Processteknik

Continuous self-learning i.e.:

Harvard Business Review articles with special interest in Leadership, Strategy & Execution and Digitalization.

2018 Executive level course – Change Management

2016 MBA level course material & books – Negotiation

2016 Executive level course material & books – Strategy

2015 Executive level course material & books – Finances for decision

making

CORE SKILLS

Structuring the big picture
Innovation and experimentation
Communication, Negotiation
Project management
Team coaching

LEADERSHIP STYLE

Combination of attention to details and broad view Personal accountability
Patient and encouraging
Inspiring through passion
Honest and open
Innovative

PROUD ACHIVEMENTS

- Designing and implementing Business Model, Strategy and Processes for Telko's polyurethanes unit
- Facilitating rethinking process for Telko Service Center and leading strategy creation for digital transformation
- During 10 years of running LVI Insinööritoimisto G. Pahlman (est. 1977), doubled the amount of HVAC design projects.
- Increased Bayer's/BaySystems' market share from 30% to 65% in polyurethanes Finland.
- Successfully led district heating plant project(s) in Russia with only Russian speaking workers, while me starting without any Russian language skills and freshly graduated from university.

WORKING HISTORY

Business Manager | Telko OY (owned by Aspo plc)

04.2018 - Present

Tasks & Achievements

- Development of polyurethane business in 16 different countries from scratch
 - o Search & evaluation of suitable principals. Result: extraordinary contract
 - Development & implementation of project strategy
 - International setup of project
 Designed strategy for project management in matrix organization
 - Coaching sales team
 - Hands-on demos and production/product optimization at customers

Business Consultant | Telko OY

04.2017 - 04.2018

Tasks & Achievements:

• Building business concept, strategy for entering new business segment

Business Owner | LVI-Insinööritoimisto G. Pahlman Oy

04.2017 - Present

CEO, Managing Director | LVI-Insinööritoimisto G. Pahlman Oy

04. 2007 - 04.2017

Tasks & Achievements:

- Reactivated company after 10 years of low activity
- Marketing & Sales
 - Doubled amount of design projects since company's start in 1977. 750 projects of different size sold and fulfilled
- Implementing new competences
 - o BIM
 - energy certificates
- Finances, administration

Branch Manager | BaySystems Northern Europe, Branch Finland (owned by Bayer AG)

05. 2002 - 04. 2007

Tasks & Achievements:

- Participation in setup of Branch Finland
- Acquisition of a PU system house in Finland
- Marketing & sales of PU systems in FI, RU, UA, Baltics
 - Strategy development & implementation
 - o Market share in FI from approx. 30% to 65% in a field of 6 competitors.
 - o Market share in UA from zero to 10%.
- Technical support
 - o Tailor-made systems for customers
 - o Participation in development of customers' products and production processes.
- Running a blending facility in Finland
 - Overall responsibility for coordinating its function, recipes, production, supply chain etc.
- HR
- Administration

Sales Manager | Suomen Tectrade Oy

Acquired by Bayer during spring 2002

06. 2001 - 05. 2002

Tasks & Achievements:

- Marketing strategy
- Sales of polyurethane systems
- Sales of machinery for PU & Plastic industry

Managing Director | Arvoputki Oy

09. 1999 - 06. 2001

Tasks & Achievements:

- Marketing & sales of district heating pipes
- Procurement strategy
- Production
- HR
- o 10-15 persons
- ITC
- Authorities

Marketing Manager | Noviter Oy

09.1995 – 09. 1999

Tasks & Achievements:

- Pricing boiler plants 3-120MW
- Visits & Support of Sales teams with customers mainly in Russia, but also in Baltics, Poland and China
- Arranging Seminars & Fairs in Russia
- Keynote Speaker at Seminars & Fairs in Russia (English and Russian language)

Project Manager | Noviter Oy

04.1993 - 09. 1995

Tasks & Achievements:

- Assembly of 3 16-24MW boiler plants for district heating in military villages in different parts of Russia. These were very public infrastructure projects, as they were based on a political agreement between Germany and Russia to bring Russian soldiers home from Germany. I was living in Moscow plus 3 more addresses in Russia.
- 3x30 employees.

LANGUAGE SKILLS

Swedish – mother tongue

English – home language

Finnish – Fluent

Russian - Good

German – small talk level

Spanish – Forgotten, could probably be awoken

C++ - basics, good skills could probably be awoken

Phyton – basics

HOBBIES

Sailing

Orienteering

Music

Learning – I'm curious on life and have constantly some learning projects going on.